YARO VOLVACH

Canada

portfolio

Summary

Software Engineer with 3 years of experience in full stack development, with a strong focus on JavaScript/React for frontend and Python for back-end programming. I'm dedicated to creating clean, efficient code and user-friendly, reusable designs. Eager to grow, I am currently enhancing my skillset by learning Rust and Solidity.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, CSS, HTML

Frameworks: Node.js, Express.js, Django, Django REST framework, React, Bootstrap

Databases: SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, DynamoDB

Developer Tools: Git, Jira, Bitbucket, Docker, VS Code, Visual Studio, PyCharm

Experience

Calystral Games GmbH | Synergy of Serra

Full-Stack Developer December 2022 - March 2024 Canada, Remote

Synergy of Serra was set to be a free-to-play PC/MacOS deckbuilding trading and collectable card game. It leveraged Polygon blockchain allowing users to trade their cards and other game artifacts in a true peer-to-peer fashion. Although the development has been shut down as of March 2024 due to financial challenges, all card data has been moved onto IPFS for a potential game reboot in the future.

Responsibilities:

- Developed front-end components with React to enable seamless updates to login credentials such as usernames, email addresses, and passwords.
- Incorporated Redux Saga for efficient management of asynchronous events and leveraged AWS services for scalable and secure backend interactions.
- Utilized Javascript to efficiently manage and update NFT metadata in AWS S3, ensuring data integrity and accessibility.
- Created test cases for the Synergy of Serra markets to test various front-end components and custom React hooks using Jest and Chai.
- Set up an automated Discord channel to provide updates from competitive games like Gods Unchained, Splinterlands, Axie Infinity, and others.
- Established a system to block crate purchases from certain countries using IP location checks and notifying users or hiding purchase options if necessary.
- Established a comprehensive POST request validation process to ensure system stability and adherence to protocols, including environment configurations checks, feature management based on system status, and handling maintenance tasks.

YARO VOLVACH

ARTEXGROUP

Software Engineer January 2021 – November 2022 Ukraine, Kharkiv

ARTEXGROUP is an IT firm that specializes in a full-cycle development of e-commerce platforms. We catered to a diverse clientele base, including local and international businesses and built custom web solutions from conceptualization to deployment.

Responsibilities:

- Developed the backend for an e-commerce website with Python, set up APIs using Django Rest Framework, and used Redis to speed up data retrieval by caching.
- Developed front-end components and custom hooks in React.js for improved application functionality and a more engaging user interface.
- Engineered the server-side logic of a web application using Node.js. Also leveraged Node.js to handle front-end data interactions with a database, optimizing for data transfer and storage.
- Handled CRUD operations in MongoDB and PostgreSQL databases.
- Developed a feature-rich shopping cart, menu, and product catalogue using React.js and Django. Integrated the platform with Stripe.js to facilitate credit card payment processing.
- Utilized Docker containers to reduce dependency conflicts and streamline deployment.

Education

2018 – 2019 *Master of Business Administration* | Sumy State University

2020 - 2021 Certificate | Hillel IT School

2023 - Certificate | University of Toronto School of Continuing Studies | CS Boot Camp